I came with an idea and I threw it out as I was listening and looking here.
I introduced Father Jim O'Donnell here four years ago and him to the back, but
I will be next year and the year after that
because what I realized sitting up here today looking around is a good view.
All these people are all from different races but we're all the ones who have
been with us.
[applause]
And the person I want to pay my deepest respect to tonight is my mother.
As I'm sitting there saying we're a black lady without the example that she set.
My father got sick with tuberculosis and spent six years in a hospital with
some acres.
We lost our house. We were never afraid because she never had a speech.
And we ended up in the projects on almost 25th Street and she would say, "Jackie,
you're the man of the house until today,
"consult. What does that mean, Mom?" I had no idea. I was seven years old at
point six and a half.
She said, "It means you got to get a job, Jackie. You got to bring some money
in the house with that."
That's where my career started. Thank God for Mom.
And I went out and I knocked on doors and I got a big group with two customers.
And I built that up to three or four and then it paid quick with five and
pretty soon I had ten or twelve customers.
And I had a big group no matter where I was. When my dad got out of the
hospital years later,
we moved out to the airport and a house that fell down after the first
sanctuary there,
the garage collapsed out of my father's car, which was a 20-year-old car at the
time.
And we all happened until he grabbed us in the ears. My brother and I, I think
that was funny
because that was the whole family walk that he had just thrown up.
But the beginnings of all that teaches you to be a family and to work.
And the money that I made gave to my mother. That was the whole way we did.
Everybody that got a job, Theresa Baby-Sapp, she gave it to Mom.
It was family that was going to win. Well, that sort of sunk into me.
And I started a business later. I worked for a guy. I was the first guy to ever
work for this gentleman.
And he was running an 80,000-hour business.
Pretty soon, he started cheating me. I walked up to him once and I said, "Mr.
So-and-so,
I don't mind that. Please don't do that again because I'm probably not going to
work for you."
He said, "No." The second time, several months later, he sure did me a hug.
What I knew I had coming, I just walked in and I said, "So-and-so, I can't do
this.
I can't work for you because I don't trust you and I don't respect you. So I'm
quitting."
And don't worry about your damn business. I will find something else to do.
I'm not going to steal this business from you.
He called me about three or four days later and he says, "Jack, I've had two
offers for the business.
I had no idea whether it was true or not."
But he says, "It's probably worth more to you than anybody else.
By this time, I had built this little $80,000 business up to about $7 million."
And he had no clue, you know, where it was coming from.
So I sat down with some bankers, my brother-in-law, Jim Forshey, and Cleveland
Trust,
and he says, "I want to know the problems before I know the successes
so I can help if I ever get to that point."
And that's how we started.
And so I'm sitting here tonight looking at all these different people from all
these different places
that are all now wanting this room being recognized in our city.
And I'm like, "Yeah." It hits me that we all have to be good to one another.
And as time went by in my business, there wasn't too much time.
I said, "If Mom did this and we got a nickel on Sunday's ice cream cone,
we'd run up to the store and buy nickel ice cream cone."
And that was a big day.
My sister and I would maybe even get a candy bar and spit it and sit down the
corner up there.
It was amazing the way you started seeing the things that are important to you.
And it was about being a family and working together.
So Mom started sharing when I got to the next step,
and I started making success happen at the company we all work.
I shared the wealth with them.
30 percent of everything that I made went to the employees.
So the way we did it, I said, "If we're going to work as hard as we're all
going to work,
then we're all going to be rewarded for it."
And so that was the beginning of our success.
The bankers, some of the bankers I had said, "Oh, you can't do that. You
shouldn't do that."
I said, "Well, this is the way we're going to do it."
So you have to have a belief in yourself and a belief in other people.
And if you're going to ask them to work as hard as you are going to work,
then you're going to share it with them.
And that went on for many, many, many years until we sold the company to a big
conglomerate.
And I retired.
My sons were still there. They bought the company back with another fellow
who made our update from the first day I ever walked in there.
And he still made it in force, and now that's a joint effort between the two of
us.
And the business has still run the same way.
Everybody in that company that works there but south is part of it, and they
just paid for it.
So I'm proud of my mother.
I'm super proud of my dad and the family that taught me how to be successful.
And I have something that we're going to change it.
And I hope it strikes some of you the same way,
because you can hear all the so-called experts that come in
start telling you how to run a business.
You can't run fast enough to get away from half of a business.
They're telling you how to be a customer, how to screw you to voice.
You can make more money.
Ask not how you do it. Ask for redemption.
So everybody here tonight, congratulations.
It's beautiful to hear these stories.
And it's beautiful that we're in these families.
We don't see color, we just see people.
So congratulations to all of us for being here.